<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Radhika Kolathumani</title>
    <description>Hi all, I am currently interning at Redhat for the summer in User Experience for the fedora project. I have started this blog to document my weekly experiences doing design challenges at redhat.
</description>
    <link>http://radhikakolathumani.github.io//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://radhikakolathumani.github.io//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 09:57:07 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 09:57:07 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The last stretch</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;prototypes&quot;&gt;Prototypes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In preparation for the flock next week, I tried to improve the prototypes and my Js code. The progress so far has been:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/calendarwidget/v2/i.html&quot;&gt;Calendar widget&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/calendarwidget/emptystate/i.html&quot;&gt;Empty State&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;bodhi&quot;&gt;Bodhi&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also concentrated on the bodhi user interview questions which are listed as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please circle which of the following age ranges applies to you:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;    1. less than 18
    2. 18-29   
    3. 30-94
    4. 50-64   
    5. 65+   
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How long have been using fedora?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;1. less than 1 year
2. 1-5 years
3. more than 5 years   
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How often do you use the bodhis web UI?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;    a. I dont use it at all    
    b. Infrequently (once per release / once every 6 months)    
    c. Sometimes (once per month or so)    
    d. Frequently (once a week)    
    c. All the time (more than once a week)    
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you use bodhis WebUI for?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;    a. Tracking package updates    
    b. Upvoting/downvoting updates    
    c. Its part of my workflow for releasing updates to packages    
    d. Its part of my testing workflow   
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Currently bodhi redirects users to koji for downloading update packages. Would you prefer bodhi to link directly to the package instead of redirecting to koji?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Would a  Bugzilla update widget like the shown below in the mockup would be useful? (Old version and the new version given below)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;    a. No I feel the older version was helpful  
    b. Yes, the new version would be super useful  
    c. It does not matter, I often check Bugzilla whenever I can myself  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Old version&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/selected/1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;            /assets/resized/480/1.png 480w,            /assets/resized/800/1.png 800w,     /assets/selected/1.png 929w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New Version&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/selected/2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;            /assets/resized/480/2.png 480w,            /assets/resized/800/2.png 800w,     /assets/selected/2.png 875w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/selected/3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;            /assets/resized/480/3.png 480w,            /assets/resized/800/3.png 800w,     /assets/selected/3.png 905w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/selected/4.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;            /assets/resized/480/4.png 480w,            /assets/resized/800/4.png 800w,     /assets/selected/4.png 905w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;While giving karma, have you ever used the middle option as shown in the figure below ?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/selected/5.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;            /assets/resized/480/5.png 480w,            /assets/resized/800/5.png 800w,     /assets/selected/5.png 860w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;a. No, I have used only +1 and –1 for feedback
b. Yes I have used it before and I know what it is used for
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;While checking for release updates, how useful was this tab shown below : (called “Release”)  ( Please refer to the tab version )&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/selected/6.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;            /assets/resized/480/6.png 480w,            /assets/resized/800/6.png 800w,            /assets/resized/1400/6.png 1400w,     /assets/selected/6.png 1878w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/selected/7.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;            /assets/resized/480/7.png 480w,     /assets/selected/7.png 554w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;a. Yes I find it very useful
b. I know about this tab but I have never found it useful
c. I don’t know what is this tab used for
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;While using Bodhis web UI, have you ever used the three icons in the “build” row of the page shown below: ( Please refer to the tab version )&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/selected/8.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;            /assets/resized/480/8.png 480w,     /assets/selected/8.png 660w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/selected/9.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;     /assets/selected/9.png 312w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;a. Yes I know about their functionality and used them often
b. No I have not used at all but I know about their functionality
c. I have no idea what these are used for
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far I am brainstorming about the question no 5; I need to think in terms of how the user would be using the widget. For this purpose, I aim to ask at least 2-3 developers and testers about the download widget. The developer that I talked to on Friday was saying he does not have the need for it in the web UI. Even though he does not use the CLI interface. He is fine by using the koji website for downloading the packages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the testers that I have approached were very keen on having the download option in the web UI itself. So far I feel it will be useful to talk to more people about the option and get their general opinion on the widgets usefulness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;this-week-in-fedora&quot;&gt;This week in Fedora&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, for this week in fedora web design project, following is the summary of the progress so far:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It would be useful if we could the add the last week stats to the fedora-community blog itself&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The visualization on the top would be a good start, we can add it to the blog&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make it as weekly post in the community blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I also attended the FAD workshop this week. This was something fun as I had go to meet people who are interested in learning inkscape. Below are some of the pictures of the event:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/fad/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;            /assets/resized/480/1.jpg 480w,            /assets/resized/800/1.jpg 800w,            /assets/resized/1400/1.jpg 1400w,     /assets/fad/1.jpg 2448w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/fad/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;            /assets/resized/480/2.jpg 480w,            /assets/resized/800/2.jpg 800w,            /assets/resized/1400/2.jpg 1400w,     /assets/fad/2.jpg 2448w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/fad/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;            /assets/resized/480/3.jpg 480w,            /assets/resized/800/3.jpg 800w,            /assets/resized/1400/3.jpg 1400w,     /assets/fad/3.jpg 2448w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://radhikakolathumani.github.io//redhat/2016/08/02/the-last-stretch.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://radhikakolathumani.github.io//redhat/2016/08/02/the-last-stretch.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>redhat</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Final phase</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;prototypes&quot;&gt;Prototypes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week I finished up the prototype for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/releasecycle/v4/i.html&quot;&gt;release widget fully&lt;/a&gt; and started coding the calendar widget &lt;a href=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/calendarwidget/i.html&quot;&gt;monthly view&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/calendarwidget/weekly/i.html&quot;&gt;weekly view&lt;/a&gt;. So far the implementation consists of the main view and weekly view (link). I am hoping to finish this by Monday evening and concentrate on prototyping the empty state widget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;more-issues&quot;&gt;More issues!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have taken some more issues for myself to solve this week, one includes a ticket in design trac namely “This week in fedora” and another which involves mobile prototyping and mockups for the hubs project. This seems like an interesting challenge and I hope to concentrate on it the coming week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;hyperkitty&quot;&gt;Hyperkitty&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally finished up the hyperkitty heuristics evaluation report after getting my feedback! The report can be viewed &lt;a href=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/releasecycle/Document+9(2).pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;bodhi&quot;&gt;Bodhi&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally had a chat with Luke about the redesign project in which I explained him about the progress we have done so far. He particularly liked the idea about the koji link in the web ui so that it becomes easier to download the packages, Currently users have to go to another website to download the packages. Further, he suggested to open an RFE for this idea as well. The RFE can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fedora-infra/bodhi/issues/874&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, the first draft of pre-interview survey is also ready and can be viewed &lt;a href=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/releasecycle/Document+15.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. I am open to suggestions in improving the survey!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://radhikakolathumani.github.io//redhat/2016/07/24/Final-phase.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://radhikakolathumani.github.io//redhat/2016/07/24/Final-phase.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>redhat</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Design Prototypes - Week 2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I focused on prototyping for the help and release cycle widget, of which I finished the release widget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding, the help widget, I still have to correct few minor problems with the drop down menu. The problem I am facing is because of the js library (chosen.js) that I have used for prototyping.
My progress so far is given below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazon link for progress of both release and help widget here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/releasecycle/i.html&quot;&gt;Release cycle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/helphelp/v2/index.html&quot;&gt;Help Help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for Bodhi, I had conducted some user interviews and had an initial one-on-one user walkthrough this week. As a first step in the process of redesign, I identified my users who were the packagers, testers and release engineers. I had hoped to finish the one-on-one with the identified user base but was unable to do since most of them had been away for the conference. However, I did have one initial session with a testers who uses the website frequently. Thanks to Mo, she helped me find a user immediately for the user walkthrough. During the walkthrough, I made my user use the website and describe the flow. This was an eye opener as I got some real good feedback from him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the use-cases that I feel were lacking from his description includes the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No download link for the koji (he was describing a drop down menu in case of multiple downloads) and command line download link as well&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Karma cycle is very confusing as he could not figure out the functionality of the untested button.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No direct contact link to the submitter.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Updates to the bugzilla.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edge-cases:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Previous searches&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Edit the replies to the thread.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was an initial feedback. I however plan to test the system with few more users, specifically with release engineers and packagers. Moreover, I will also be updating the Bodhi redesign wiki page as I proceed further in my process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also attended the patternfly community meeting to better understand their process and the idea behind it. They basically include different components (both from bootstrap as well as their own) after small rigorous sprints. I believe this methodology could be really useful for our fedora-bootsrap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving on, I also implemented an empty state ui design for our hubs which have not been release yet. I wanted the pattern to be more direct and captivating at the same time. The final design can be seen &lt;a href=&quot;https://pagure.io/fedora-hubs/issue/169&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://radhikakolathumani.github.io//redhat/2016/07/17/design-prototypes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://radhikakolathumani.github.io//redhat/2016/07/17/design-prototypes.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>redhat</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Design prototypes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week my mentor had suggested that it would be great if I am able to code the front end for the designs that I had implemented. I thought it would be a great way to see how my designs would be developed and implemented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this week, I concentrated on implementing the visual rework as well the front end code for the issues 98 and 63.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the issue 98, I constructed the accordion through javascript and implemented the drop downs through chosen.js. I had to be super careful about using the js libraries online as I had make sure they had appropriate licenses. The chosen.js that I have used for this project is under MIT license. Even though I ran into multiple problems in the style sheet,I managed to implement the first few elements of the visual design. Further, the rework for the visual design and the code for implementing it can be seen here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://helphelp.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/&quot;&gt;prototype link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/HelpWidgetRework.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;            /assets/resized/480/HelpWidgetRework.png 480w,            /assets/resized/800/HelpWidgetRework.png 800w,            /assets/resized/1400/HelpWidgetRework.png 1400w,     /assets/HelpWidgetRework.png 2260w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, I still have to work on implementing the chosen.js correctly since I want the dropdown to have the text input functionality as well. I will be working on this coming week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another issue that I had worked this week included the release cycle. I implemented this by using a responsive rectangle and overlayed all the images over it. So far the output looks like this. There are some portions that are not responsive yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://releasecycle.s3-website-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/&quot;&gt;prototype link - tested only on firefox so far&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next week goal would be to make the slider stop when the date of release/ freeze has been reached.  I am thinking this could be implemented by using the detailed timeline document which I referred from the fedora release cycle wiki. The slider would act like a timer which could be implemented by js. Further, there are some portions of this release cycle which are not yet fully responsive. I will be addressing that as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://radhikakolathumani.github.io//redhat/2016/07/10/design-and-code.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://radhikakolathumani.github.io//redhat/2016/07/10/design-and-code.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>redhat</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Summit and the Bodhi</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This week was an interesting week as I got to attend the summit talks, participated in a remote usability testing and finally was awed by my mentor Mo’s storytelling capabilities!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started off this week by working on feedback for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://pagure.io/fedora-hubs/issue/91&quot;&gt;calendar widget&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://pagure.io/fedora-hubs/issue/63&quot;&gt;release cycle&lt;/a&gt;. This was my third iteration and I was making sure that I had incorporated the user comments and feedback accurately. The feedback for the calendar widget mainly involved correcting the visual layout of the widget. So far I had been concentrating a lot on interaction design and developer constraints. I wanted to spend time and improve my visual design skills. The third iterative feedback focused mainly on improving the visual aspects of the design. For the purpose of the improvements, I researched several UI patterns online to gather some inspiration for the rework. After researching online, I figured that the minimalist design approach with the use of one main color for highlights would work well for the feedback. I tried this approach keeping in mind all the use cases that I have incorporated so far. Thus, the end iterative design could be seen here in the links listed above. I am hoping that the users will like the new approach and will provide the feedback for the widgets accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another interesting discussion that I had this week was with my mentor Mo and Ryan Lerch on Bodhi. Bodhi facilities the process of publishing updates for Fedora-based software distribution system. My understanding of Bodhi was limited to knowing that it is just a build and release system. During our discussion, Mo’s explanation was what struck me to be one of the best available descriptions of the system. She explained to me to think of Bodhi as an organic potato farm. The farm will harvest these potatoes and transport them to the nearest supermarket. After reaching the market,  each potato is thoroughly inspected for quality. This is usually done by the quality inspectors who vote and mark each potato for its quality. Translating this to the software jargon, several software packages (potatoes) are marked for their quality in the scale of 1-3 with 3 being the highest. The potato inspectors, in this case, are the release engineers who vote for the quality of each and every software before its release. Supporting them would be users from open source community who can also participate in the voting process. Whoa! Clear and succinct explanation! I hope I had the capability to come up with such great explanations which could be useful for even a seven-year-old!. Moving on, I will be working towards finding my potato inspectors the coming week for user research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the fedora-bootstrap, I had started adding the necessary components to the index.html. But I am unable to push it to pagure as I am getting a 403 error. This might be due to the fact that I do not have the right permissions. I will be working on solving this issue next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I completed my heuristics on Hyperkitty. I will be posting the recommendations on this blog next week. Further, I also had a chance to participate in a remote usability testing over blue jeans. It was a good learning experience as I got to know how people perceive a particular design choice. Their feedback and suggestions were invaluable to the design process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, with all the action happening at the summit, I did not want to miss a single broadcast at the Westford office. However, I was able to attend only one session this week by Corinne Warnshuis, Executive Director of “Girl Develop It”. Nevertheless, I was doing my part by retweeting some of my manager Paul’s tweets :P !.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More on this discussion by Corrinne, I applaud her efforts into making develop girl it a force to reckon with within the community. I myself was a part of “Girl Develop It” in the Seattle/Ann Arbor area and used to attend their casual meetups. I remember when I had just started to learn to code, I was afraid of asking for help. Even if I am stuck, it was hard to find someone willing to understand and provide the right guidance. “Girl Develop It” made that learning process easier for me by providing the right mentorship and guidance throughout my earlier attempts at coding. Not only I was receiving feedback but I had similar people like me trying to understand and develop confidence while learning to code. During her talk at the Summit too, she mentioned about some success stories that had helped many women across the United States. I attended this talk along with women who were a part of the Women Leadership Community-Westford. Further, I would like to thank Garima (Performance Team) for putting all the efforts to arranging this meetup and discussion for us that day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2016 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://radhikakolathumani.github.io//redhat/2016/07/03/summit-and-bodhi.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://radhikakolathumani.github.io//redhat/2016/07/03/summit-and-bodhi.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>redhat</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Issue 98, HyperKitty, Fedora-Apps</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This week I focused on iterating on the feedback I received for the previous &lt;a href=&quot;https://pagure.io/fedora-hubs/issue/63&quot;&gt;issue&lt;/a&gt;  and worked on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://pagure.io/fedora-hubs/issue/98&quot;&gt;help widget for the hubs&lt;/a&gt;. I also found something that caught my interest and wanted to improve the design of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.fedoraproject.org/&quot;&gt;Fedora Apps website&lt;/a&gt;. Lastly, I also conducted hyper kitty’s heuristics evaluation for the purpose of evaluating the design choices for the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;issue-98&quot;&gt;Issue 98&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the first task I worked on this week. The issue expresses a need for the user to have the same functionality of #help in IRC, as a widget in the hub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following is a high-level overview of the flow: The user asks for help in the IRC channel which might be specified in a semi-structured format. The Json has to be populated and it is sent to the back-end. Next, it gets pushed to the help widget where it is converted into a format which is understandable to the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some use cases that I can think of are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How would the user specify in IRC channel ? (Tagging maybe one solution)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How will we display the message in the help widget?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What all we would want to show in the help widget?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to configure the help widget?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Further, I wanted to keep in mind the developer constraints as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;paper-mockups&quot;&gt;Paper Mockups&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/IMG_20160626_191958.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;            /assets/resized/480/IMG_20160626_191958.jpg 480w,            /assets/resized/800/IMG_20160626_191958.jpg 800w,            /assets/resized/1400/IMG_20160626_191958.jpg 1400w,     /assets/IMG_20160626_191958.jpg 3264w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-design&quot;&gt;Final Design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the final design I followed the fedora guidelines and design standards for this project. The final design is provided below and feedback on the design can be provided &lt;a href=&quot;https://pagure.io/fedora-hubs/issue/98&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/HelpWidgetFinal.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;            /assets/resized/480/HelpWidgetFinal.png 480w,            /assets/resized/800/HelpWidgetFinal.png 800w,            /assets/resized/1400/HelpWidgetFinal.png 1400w,     /assets/HelpWidgetFinal.png 2260w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;fedora-apps&quot;&gt;Fedora-apps&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is project that I took on my own as I wanted to make the fedora apps front page easily understandable. Currently the categorization of projects is incorrect in the graph. Furthermore, the graph is not easily readable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this purpose, Mo and I had a discussion to identify the end users of this website. We concluded that our primary users would include system administrators, developers and users of the open source community. To improve the information on this page, we thought to clearly indicate the software category and software name. Furthermore, we decided to show some additional information about the software when the user clicks it. Following these discussions, I started gathering information for categorizing the apps accurately based on the software name, category and their description.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;hyperkitty-herustics-evaluation&quot;&gt;Hyperkitty Herustics evaluation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week I also did a heuristics evalaution on Hyper Kitty which a django based archiver for the mailman suite allowing the users to starts new threads, reply to mails and mark them as favorites,  I focused on analysing the wesbite with regards to the principles that we have been taught in class. I will be updating the heuristics in a separate blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://radhikakolathumani.github.io//redhat/2016/06/26/issue98.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://radhikakolathumani.github.io//redhat/2016/06/26/issue98.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>redhat</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Release cycle</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The third week, I spent my time working on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://pagure.io/fedora-hubs/issue/63&quot;&gt;release cycle issue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;problem-statement&quot;&gt;Problem Statement&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea was to depict the fedora 24 release cycle for the web and the mobile version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;brainstorming&quot;&gt;Brainstorming&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read up the document on how the release document works in the fedora 24 release cycle: &lt;a href=&quot;https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Releases/24/Schedule&quot;&gt;Schedule&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://fedorapeople.org/groups/schedule/f-24/f-24-devel-tasks.html&quot;&gt;Task list&lt;/a&gt;. I had realized that the detailed milestone document had the same dates. After a quick discussion with pingou and mo, we figured that the final dates matter the most. This cycle was represented as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Branching&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alpha freeze starts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alpha release&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alpha freeze ends&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beta freeze starts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beta release&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beta freeze ends&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Release freeze starts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Release&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;paper-mockups&quot;&gt;Paper Mockups&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I quickly sketched out some ideas for the mockups as shown below&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/Paper3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;            /assets/resized/480/Paper3.jpg 480w,            /assets/resized/800/Paper3.jpg 800w,            /assets/resized/1400/Paper3.jpg 1400w,     /assets/Paper3.jpg 3264w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-design&quot;&gt;Final Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I figured that showing the showing the milestones accurately would be easy as compared to showing the detailed version of the release cycle. Further, the breadcrumb navigation pattern would be easy to show the timeline between the different cycle stages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/InfoReleaseCycle.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;            /assets/resized/480/InfoReleaseCycle.png 480w,            /assets/resized/800/InfoReleaseCycle.png 800w,            /assets/resized/1400/InfoReleaseCycle.png 1400w,     /assets/InfoReleaseCycle.png 1523w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mobile-design&quot;&gt;Mobile design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/Mobile-View.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;            /assets/resized/480/Mobile-View.png 480w,            /assets/resized/800/Mobile-View.png 800w,            /assets/resized/1400/Mobile-View.png 1400w,     /assets/Mobile-View.png 2285w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;visual-design&quot;&gt;Visual Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This infographic required the use of principle of closure as evident from the figure below for showing the forward direction. The color palette and fonts are in accordance with the fedora design guidelines.  &lt;br /&gt;
The use of symbols and dates further explains the stage at which the cycle is in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/Closure.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;            /assets/resized/480/Closure.png 480w,            /assets/resized/800/Closure.png 800w,     /assets/Closure.png 1019w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;user-comments&quot;&gt;User Comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pagure.io/fedora-hubs/issue/63&quot;&gt;Fedora Issue link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users had mentioned that the release cycle happens only for a particular day unlike the pattern shown in the picture depicts that the release happened for a lengthy period of time. So I prototyped the newer version showing the arrow for release day smaller than the rest. This helps depicts the time period for which the release happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;iteration-1&quot;&gt;Iteration 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/InfoReleaseCycleRework.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;            /assets/resized/480/InfoReleaseCycleRework.png 480w,            /assets/resized/800/InfoReleaseCycleRework.png 800w,            /assets/resized/1400/InfoReleaseCycleRework.png 1400w,     /assets/InfoReleaseCycleRework.png 1628w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, one particular user did not like the idea of rawhide shown in the picture. But I wanted to include the master (rawhide) for the purpose of explaining the branch and master. So I deemphasized the master by reducing the size and making current branch cycle more prominent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;jekyll-update&quot;&gt;Jekyll Update&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had problems with the resizing the images in jekyll and figured installing the jekyll responsive plugin would help with the resizing of the images. However I realized that github (on which I hosted the website) does not support the required plugin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I solved this issue by building the jekyll website locally first and just pushed the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt; folder contents to Github.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fedora-bootstrap&quot;&gt;Fedora Bootstrap&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had attended the new pattern fly website release this week, I really the liked the idea of vertical navbar for navigation. After using the website I wanted to have the same level of documentation for fedora bootsrap as they have for patten fly. I discussed this idea with mo and she wanted me to work on the idea for the coming week.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2016 10:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://radhikakolathumani.github.io//redhat/2016/06/19/Release-Cycle.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://radhikakolathumani.github.io//redhat/2016/06/19/Release-Cycle.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>redhat</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>PlusPlusWidget</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am in my second week and I am still getting used to using inkscape. I recently found out that inkscape has many functionalities that photoshop does not have. This was especially useful in case of importing and exporting images by directing selecting the required image or drawing. I found out that it is really useful feature that Adobe generally allows it by exporting the entire document. As I am starting to use it more and more, I figured inkscape to better and faster for vector graphics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing I worked on this week was Jekyll, I finally figured a way to upload my images and mockups. For starters Jekyll is a blog aware static website generator which allows users to share and post their material online. I am finding it very easy to use as compared to WordPress or any other blogging websites available online. Further, it has also allowed to me practice using the Linux command line. I am becoming better and faster at it each day. Thankfully due to the number of mistakes I have committed so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well as for the rest, I also attended the lunch and learn session which is organized by redhat weekly. It gives us the chance to post and ask questions about redhat in general. I attended the Arun Oberoi session this week as he talked about how useful is to make mistakes. I remember in my initial days I was feeling under the weather about how many silly mistakes I had been making so far. His speech emphasized on how important is make mistakes and quickly learn and improve. This actually proved to be a really useful suggestion and I intend to apply that to my internship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the tickets I worked on this week included the PlusPLus widget (https://pagure.io/fedora-hubs/issue/57). I found this to be a really interesting widget to work on, as it involved designing an experience similar to the one in IRC (without really using the IRC integration).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;brainstorming&quot;&gt;Brainstorming&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I brainstormed and sketched before the final mock up (which is posted here). I analyzed the pros and cons of each use-case that I had explored. After the initial brainstorming session, I quickly read up on how the widget will work under the hood. Currently the data for the ++ in IRC is stored in a python shelve file. The way it is written it is not suitable to be shared between the zodbot and the hubs page. So designing this widget might require a total rework of the zodbot plugin. Keeping this constraint in mind, I sketched some mockups for the widget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;target-audience&quot;&gt;Target Audience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a first step to the design process, I understood the target audience for the hubs as someone who contributes to the open source community and wants to keep abreast of the all major happenings inside the community.The idea is to update the user about the various development likes events, meetings etc happening throughout the hubs. One simple idea would be through the personal calendar widget. &lt;br /&gt;
Paper mockups&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;paper-mockups&quot;&gt;Paper Mockups&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sketched some ideas for the widget and the designs for the symbol “++”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/Paper2.1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;            /assets/resized/480/Paper2.1.jpg 480w,            /assets/resized/800/Paper2.1.jpg 800w,            /assets/resized/1400/Paper2.1.jpg 1400w,     /assets/Paper2.1.jpg 3264w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/Paper2.2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;            /assets/resized/480/Paper2.2.jpg 480w,            /assets/resized/800/Paper2.2.jpg 800w,            /assets/resized/1400/Paper2.2.jpg 1400w,     /assets/Paper2.2.jpg 3264w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-design&quot;&gt;Final Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exploring all the use cases in general, I prototyped the final mockups in inkscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;profile-page-1&quot;&gt;Profile page 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/Profile-Page.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;            /assets/resized/480/Profile-Page.png 480w,            /assets/resized/800/Profile-Page.png 800w,     /assets/Profile-Page.png 1032w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;profile-page-2&quot;&gt;Profile page 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/Profile-Page2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;            /assets/resized/480/Profile-Page2.png 480w,            /assets/resized/800/Profile-Page2.png 800w,     /assets/Profile-Page2.png 856w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;subscribers-page&quot;&gt;Subscriber’s page&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/SubscriberPage.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;            /assets/resized/480/SubscriberPage.png 480w,     /assets/SubscriberPage.png 790w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The user profile will a ++ icon next to the picture which would allow any subscriber to give the ++ to the user. I thought this would be easy for the subscriber to find the particular icon since the ++ needs to be given to the user and not the action&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Once the subscriber gives a ++ to someone the icon then grays out. This is designed keeping in the mind the karma cycle, the icon becomes available after 6 months.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Another use case that I can think of is what if the subscriber wanted to know the karma cycle of any user he/she is subscribed to ?. For this purpose, I kept a text field entry for the user’s page, Through which they can check their own and their subscriber’s current karma by using the IRC command karma username. (karma ryan). However this widget can be only accessible to the owner of that page.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The subscriber page will have a karma notification in the stream. Whereas for the owner’s page, the stream will indicate the current karma for that user.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I followed the same color scheme as per the fedora design guidelines and the font used is open sans.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Lastly, I have designed the widget keeping in mind the mobile responsiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving on, I do have some improvements that I can think of in this design&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The name of the widget can be changed to something better ( instead of plus plus )&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The ++ icon can be designed more effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Need to think more in terms of where the widget could be placed more strategically, one way that I can think of is by applying the fitt’s law.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;design-guidelines&quot;&gt;Design guidelines&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I followed the standard design guidelines for font and color palette for fedora.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2016 10:10:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://radhikakolathumani.github.io//redhat/2016/06/19/issue-51.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://radhikakolathumani.github.io//redhat/2016/06/19/issue-51.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>redhat</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My First Week</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The first week at Redhat was an amazing learning experience in which I  spent time getting familiarized with the  fedora ecosystem. For starters fedora hubs is like collaboration and communication tool which allows both developers and non-developers to easily share ideas and contribute to the open source community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;problem-statement&quot;&gt;Problem Statement&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was assigned some issues to resolve in the fedora-hubs project. Issues category includes ideas or any other problem that needs to be resolved. These issues are discussed in pagure, a (much like github) channel for hosting Fedora projects. The first issue that was assigned to me was to design a personal calendar for the subscriber’s personal hub page. The link can be found here https://pagure.io/fedora-hubs/issue/91 (requires a FAS account login). For this process, I followed the User Centered design methodology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;brainstorming&quot;&gt;Brainstorming&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mo (My awesome mentor at Redhat ) and I initially brainstormed about the initial design use cases and edge cases for this widget. Some of the important use cases that were discussed included:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The widget can show all of the meeting times for the teams the user is a member of&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It will allow the user to click on the meeting in the calendar widget to get more details about the time / place, etc&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Real time update about the meeting which might be taking place in the hub&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A meeting suggestion feature which will be based on meetbot logs&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were some edge cases like changing your attendance to no, IRC integration. But considering how useful that might be to our users, Mo and I thought it will be reasonable enough to implement the important use cases first and then try to incorporate more based on the users feedback on the mockups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;target-audience&quot;&gt;Target Audience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a first step to the design process, I understood the the target audience for the hubs as someone who contributes to the open source community and wants to keep abreast of the all major happenings inside the community.The idea is to update the user about the various development likes events, meetings etc happening throughout the hubs. One simple idea would be through the personal calendar widget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;design-process&quot;&gt;Design Process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started the design process by implementing the paper mockups of the calendar widgets. The methodology that I followed can be found here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;paper-mockups&quot;&gt;Paper Mockups&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/Paper1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;            /assets/resized/480/Paper1.jpg 480w,            /assets/resized/800/Paper1.jpg 800w,            /assets/resized/1400/Paper1.jpg 1400w,     /assets/Paper1.jpg 3264w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The paper mockups that I designed for this process included  two different types of calendar widget mainly I.e monthly view and weekly view. I decided on two different views because it would be easier for the user to see the upcoming meetings for the this week and the next. This weekly view widget is more functional as the meetings happen weekly and it is easier to keep track on all current meetings for the week. Further, the calendar view would give them a glimpse of upcoming meetings in a particular month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;final-visual-design&quot;&gt;Final Visual Design&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the final visual design I chose some of the old bootstrap-mockups designed by mo and updated them using the ideas given above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/FInalMockup.svg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;            /assets/resized/480/FInalMockup.svg 480w,            /assets/resized/800/FInalMockup.svg 800w,     /assets/FInalMockup.svg 1052w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Happening now will let the user know of the meetings happening currently&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This link would also allow the user to go to the IRC.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The widget also has suggested meetings which could be based on the frequency of visits to a particular meetings (based on meetbot logs)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Two different calendar views(e.g weekly and monthly) which gives more control to the user. They choose the type of the view depending on their frequency of meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;choice-of-color-scheme&quot;&gt;Choice of Color Scheme&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The color scheme that I chose included the fedora logo blue which I carried throughout the widget. Further, I made use the combination of warm and cool colors to provide differentiation between the pop-ups and buttons. The color scheme used for this widget is split complementary harmony.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;mobile-desktop-version&quot;&gt;Mobile Desktop Version&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I designed this widget keeping the mind the mobile responsiveness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;points-to-ponder&quot;&gt;Points to ponder&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I believe if we are designing for the open source community, we need to factor in the some of the disadvantages regarding this particular design specially with regards to the people with accessibility issues.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Further, it will be great to have some documentation similar in lines of pattern fly for our fedora project.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2016 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://radhikakolathumani.github.io//redhat/2016/06/19/My-First-Week.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://radhikakolathumani.github.io//redhat/2016/06/19/My-First-Week.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>redhat</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
